Guide to the Lambda Alpha International Records, 1931-1986
Lambda Alpha International records, 1931-1986
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lambda Alpha International records, 1931-1986
2917
Lambda Alpha International.
6.9 cubic ft.
Records, scrapbook, publications, correspondence, and photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes records of Lambda Alpha International, formerly the International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha, which was established in 1931 at Northwestern University by a group of students of land economics and real estate as an honorary professional fraternity to foster the study of land economics.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Lambda Alpha International, formerly the International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha, was established on February 23, 1931 at Northwestern University by a group of students of land economics and real estate as an honorary professional fraternity to foster the study of land economics. The first chapter, the Ely Chapter in Chicago, was named after Dr. Richard T. Ely for his role as "Father of Land Economics." Other chapters include the George Washington Chapter, Washington, D.C.; the Dixie States Chapter, Atlanta, Georgia; the Flagler Chapter, Miami, Florida; the Golden Gate Chapter, San Francisco, California; the Simcoe Chapter, Toronto, Canada; and the Los Angeles, Philadelphia, San Diego, Honolulu, Tulsa, Minneapolis, New York City, Phoenix, Seattle, and St. Louis Chapters. Membership is by invitation and election only.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Early records consist of a scrapbook of clippings and memorabilia, 1931-1933, and membership lists. Other records of the organization date from 1949 to the present and consist of the charter, constitution, bylaws and materials concerning fraternity history, and bylaws of regional chapters. Also, financial records; correspondence of the presidents' secretaries; chapter records including notices and reports of meetings; agendas and minutes of business and special meetings, and membership data; photographs and publications, including the fraternity journal, newsletters, and yearbooks. Includes records of the Land Economics Foundation and information on the various Biennial Congresses of Lambda Alpha.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lambda Alpha International.; Lambda Alpha International.; Land Economics Foundation.
Subjects:
Trade and professional associations.; Land economics.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Lambda Alpha International Records
  - Articles of Incorporation, photo copy, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution: original draft and reprint, 1931, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Constitution and revised edition, 1959, c. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Initiation Ritual (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - By-laws of Regional Chapters: Dixie, Ely, Flagler, George Washington, Golden Gate, Los Angeles - 1967, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - By-laws of Regional Chapters: New York, Philadelphia, Simcoe - 1967, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History, c. 1955, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Awards by Lambda Alpha; correspondence, news releases - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chapter Announcements: Ely (Chicago), George Washington (Washington, D.C.), Golden Gate (San Francisco) 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chapter Announcements: Los Angeles, New York Area, Philadelphia 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chapter Expansion - Correspondence, nomination forms, clippings, photos, memorandum: Atlanta chapter, Michigan chapter, New York chapter, Philadelphia chapter, St. Louis chapter, Toronto chapter, Rho Epsilon merger 1948-1966, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Newsletters - drafts and memoranda, Memorial issue 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nomination forms (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Urban Land Institute - brochure and envelope, Technical Bulletin #60, "Changing Patterns of Land Economics" by Homer Hoyt (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook of news clippings and memorabilia, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 16-18)
  - Presidential Photographs: Douglas V. Cannon (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Biennial Congress - Correspondence, agenda, news releases of election 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Directory receipts, correspondence, general ledger sheet 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - General - Grand Council - correspondence, miscellany, membership list 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Grand Chapter - Disbursements: correspondence, invoices, statements, treasurer's reports 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Grand Chapter - Constitution: correspondence concerning interim edicts and constitution revision 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Grand Chapter Officers: instructions, correspondence concerning organizational matters, 2 newsletters 1957, 1960-67 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Grand Chapter - Treasurer's reports to officers: correspondence and reports including bank statements, schedules of accounts, reports of membership, etc. 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Grand Congress; correspondence concerning nomination of Grand Chapter offices, minutes of nomination committee 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Income taxes - evidence to support application for tax exempt status: correspondence, summary of receipts and disbursements, general ledger sheets 1962-67 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Information - Treasurer: general instructions, forms used by treasurer, correspondence concerning official jeweller 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Land Economics Foundation and Archives correspondence 1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Land Economics Journal - correspondence concerning Lambda Alpha subscriptions 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Treasurer's Records: correspondence, invoices, statements 1949-1961 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Chapter Returns - Dixie States (Atlanta, Georgia): correspondence, membership lists, cash journal 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Ely (Chicago) - correspondence, membership lists, cash journal 1949-1967 (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
  - Flagler (Miami, Florida) - correspondence, cash journal 1961-67 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - George Washington (Washington, D.C.) - correspondence, membership lists, cash journal 1957-1967 (Box 1, Folder 38-39)
  - Golden Gate (San Francisco) - correspondence, membership list, cash journal, San Francisco Redevelopment Agency Report 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Los Angeles - correspondence, by-laws, membership lists, programs, cash journal 1955-1967 (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
  - New York Area - correspondence, cash journal 1949-1967 (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
  - Philadelphia (proposed) - clipping from Quarterly Newsletter 1967 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Simcoe (Toronto, Canada) - correspondence, constitution 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Bank statements, cancelled checks, treasurer's records, record of bank reconciliation, deposit slips, journals, general ledger (assets, revenue, expense, balance sheets) 1949-1967 (Box 2)
  - General Counsel and Executive Secretary 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 1-20)
  - General Counsel, Executive Secretary-Treasurer 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 21-48)
  - Executive secretary - Wally Mackey file 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 49-52)
  - Hugo-Brunt, M.: member, Simcoe Chapter, International Historian, member Journal Search committee Finch, H.F.: Lambda Alpha - Cornell Project, Lambda Alpha brochure 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 53-55)
  - Ely Chapter Officers 1931-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer - Grand Chapter 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Secretary - Grand Chapter 1961-1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Membership 1961-1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Grand Chapter Meeting 1959 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Publicity 1949-1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Secretary 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer 1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Directory 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Reading File - Grand Chapter 1959-62 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Handbook 1950 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 25th Anniversary Membership Roster 1955 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Grand Chapter - Rituals, etc. 1955-1961 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Grand Chapter re Directory 1961-1964 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Grand Chapter 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Lost Members 1964 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Biennial Congress 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18-20)
  - Badgley 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Hendee 1962 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Harrington, J.J., & Co. Harrington, J.J., Jr., Chicago 1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - re Directory 1963 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Biennial Congress 1963 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - President - Grand Chapter 1958-1965 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Stationary - Lambda Alpha and miscellany 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Grand Chapter 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Roster material and Mailing Lists 1956-1960 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - New Chapters 1961 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Grand Chapter Miscellany 1957-1963 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Grand Chapter 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Grand Chapter 1955-1963 (Box 4, Folder 33-35)
  - Flagler Chapter 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Golden Gate Chapter 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Ely Chapter Membership Roster 1960 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Ely Chapter Membership Roster 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Ely Grand Chapter 1933-1956 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Ely Grand Chapter 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Ely Grand Chapter 1960 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Dixie States Chapter - Reports of Chapter Progress 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Dixie States - Grand Chapter 1959-1965 (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
  - Philadelphia - Grand Chapter 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - New York - Grand Chapter 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Los Angeles - Grand Chapter 1958-1965 (Box 4, Folder 49-50)
  - Simcoe Chapter Membership List 1969 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - George Washington Chapter Roster (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Papers Offered at the Biennial Congress 1969 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Kellough - Chairman Urban Affairs Award Case 1971 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - W. Kellough - Simcoe Chapter 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Vitae of Members (whose publications we do not have) (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - W.R. Kellough - Chairman, Banquet and Housing Committee 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Kellough - Biennial Congress 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 58-59)
  - Programs 1955-1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Congress 1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Golden Gate Chapter 1965-70 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, programs, and photos concerning present officers and directors of the Los Angeles Chapter and the new delegation 1968-1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Individual photographs, A-C (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Individual photographs, D-J (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Individual photographs, K-M (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Individual photographs, N-R (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Individual photographs, S-W (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Robert C. Klove - correspondence 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Los Angeles miscellaneous correspondence 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Ely Chapter 1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - J.W. Greathead 1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Minutes 1976 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - International Congress 1977 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Interview: Arthur Bohnen and James Massey, Memphis Chapter 1977 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Ely Chapter 1980 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Minutes - Land Economics Foundation 1981-89 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Philadelphia Chapter 1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Minutes 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Keynotes International (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, reports, etc. 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Constitution 1983 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Toronto Congress - selected papers 1983 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Executive Committee Meeting 1984 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - "Capitol Solutions" 1985 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - "The Ricks Report" 1985 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Keynotes International, Selected Papers from Biennial Congress, etc. 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Minutes 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Alexander Redevelopment and Housing Authority 1988 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - "About Us" - David L. Callies 1989 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - "About Us" - Harry Chaddick 1988 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - "About Us" - Tom Dyke 1988 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - "About Us" - Colden Florance 1988 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - "About Us" - Don Hendry Fulton 1989 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - "About Us" - Jeffrey Heller 1988 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - "About Us" - Larry Laukka (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - "About Us" - Edward J. Levy 1987 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - "About Us" - Robert M. Parks (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - "About Us" - Walter N. Marks 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - "About Us" 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - "About Us" 1989 (Box 5, Folder 42-52)
  - "About Us" 1990 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - "About Us" 1989 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Biennial Congress 1991 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Biographical Sketches 1966 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Lambda Alpha - Cornell University Agreements (H. Finch) 1968-1974 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Ely Chapter Reports,1985-1993 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - George Washington Chapter Announcements 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Philadelphia and Puget Sound Chapters Announcements1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Community Assistance Program Reports 1988-1989, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Savings and Loan Journal, May 1955 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - American Society of Landscape Architects (ASLA) Meeting Manual 1962 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Lambda Alpha - Cornell University agreements (H. Finch) 1968-1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with H. Finch especially re. L.A. Brochure 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Donors and Archives Content 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Lambda Alpha Accession File (outdated) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Lambda Alpha Literary Archives at Cornell University, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Urban Development a Guide to the Lambda Alpha Archives at Cornell University
  - Lambda Alpha 25th Anniversary Membership Roster 1955, 1 (Box 7)
  - Lambda Alpha Land Economics Journal: vol. 1, Spring 1978; vol.2, 1980; vol. 3, 1981 (50th Anniversary Issue), 2 (Box 7)
  - Lambda Alpha Rosters 1965-1971, 3 (Box 7)
  - Lambda Alpha Year Book and Roster 1976, 4 (Box 7)
  - Lambda Alpha Year Book 1977, 5 (Box 7)
  - Los Angeles Chapter Membership Roster 1969-1970, 6 (Box 7)
  - Video Cassette: "Profiles in Courage" converted from 16mm film by John F. Kennedy Foundation - film was at least 25 years old 1985, 7 (Box 7)
  - Video Cassette: Richard T. Ely - "Profiles in Courage", 8 (Box 7)
  - "Cameron Vallet" - A Public Housing Success Story, Alexandria, Virginia 1988, 9 (Box 7)